<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Smart Healthcare | PEILab</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/tags/smart-healthcare/</link><atom:link href="https://peilab.netlify.app/tags/smart-healthcare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Smart Healthcare</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © The Pervasive Edge Intelligence Laboratory Reserved. 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://peilab.netlify.app/media/logo_hude7c550c9b1c4d0119cb1e6619a815ae_62586_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>Smart Healthcare</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/tags/smart-healthcare/</link></image><item><title>Radiation-free Spine Reconstruction and Posture Analysis Techniques with 3D Imaging</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/radiation-free-spine-reconstruction-and-posture-analysis-techniques-with-3d-imaging/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/radiation-free-spine-reconstruction-and-posture-analysis-techniques-with-3d-imaging/</guid><description>&lt;p>Scoliosis is a sideways curvature of the spine that occurs most often during thegrowth spurt just before puberty. According to the survey and statistics of China Child Development Center, more than 20% teens have scoliosis. In addition to myopia and obesity, scoliosis has become the third biggest killer of youth health. According to some relevant survey data, 60% of teenagers have different degrees of posture problems. Early prevention and early treatment is the key of adolescent posture problems. Children who have mild scoliosis need to be monitored closely, usually with X-rays,to see if the curve is getting worse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At present, the mainstream screening method is still manual detection, which has require patient naturally stands and bends at 90 degrees and the doctor makes a judgment based on the spinal line and morphological changes. However, such method has low efficiency and low accuracy and facing the severe shortage of physiotherapists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile, during the COVID-19 epidemic, to help more people with rehabilitation needs realize remote screening and tracking and real-time AI monitoring of sports rehabilitation at home. A mobile-based posture screening algorithm and real-time exercise rehabilitation tracking algorithm are proposed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this project, we will design a 3D back image analysis method using commercial RGB-D to achieve low-cost, non-radiation, and sufficient accuracy of spine analysis and scoliosis screening. However, the analysis of the back image based on RGB-D is not simple and has the following three major challenges: (1) The back of the human body is an irregular curved surface, which is difficult to describe with some parametric models. (2) The point cloud image measured by commercial sensors is relatively sparse and has strong noise, and it is difficult to directly obtain the shape of the back. (3) The relationship between the back image and the spine shape is fuzzy.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure id="figure-hardware-design-and-compoments">
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >
&lt;img alt="Hardware Design and Compoments"
src="https://peilab.netlify.app/project/radiation-free-spine-reconstruction-and-posture-analysis-techniques-with-3d-imaging/picture1.svg"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>
Hardware Design and Compoments
&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>To address these challenges, we propose an automated all-in-one machine that performs comprehensive and accurate analysis, evaluation, and diagnosis of human posture: analysis items are in addition to common body dimensions. It also includes three-dimensional reconstruction of human spine based on infrared, foot pressure analysis, XO legs, pelvic deformation analysis and other functions; it is a set of comprehensive posture evaluation system with clinical significance in the real sense.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure id="figure-posture-analysis-algorithms">
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >
&lt;img alt="Posture analysis algorithms"
src="https://peilab.netlify.app/project/radiation-free-spine-reconstruction-and-posture-analysis-techniques-with-3d-imaging/picture2.svg"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>
Posture analysis algorithms
&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>We also develop a Dr. Body APP, which uses AI algorithm to screen scoliosis, XO legs, high and low shoulders and other unhealthy postures through the photos of the back of the human body of the mobile phone for screening and severity classification; the use of a single photo of the human body for three-dimensional reconstruction of the human body for posture analysis and dimension measurement; Provide users with a variety of sports rehabilitation online courses, and record sports videos for intelligent action correction and analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure id="figure-app-record-user-data-and-provide-personalized-follow-up-service">
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >
&lt;img alt="App record user data and provide personalized follow-up service"
src="https://peilab.netlify.app/project/radiation-free-spine-reconstruction-and-posture-analysis-techniques-with-3d-imaging/picture3.svg"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>
App record user data and provide personalized follow-up service
&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Innovation competition awards:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First Prize of Hong Kong University Student Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition (2020); Hong Kong Social Enterprise Competition (HKSEC2019) Intellectual Property Ambassador Award; &amp;ldquo;Weining Cup&amp;rdquo; International AI Medical Challenge First Prize (2019), et.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Anti-Occlusion Human Pose Estimation for Scoliosis Rehabilitation</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/anti-occlusion-human-pose-estimation-for-scoliosis-rehabilitation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/anti-occlusion-human-pose-estimation-for-scoliosis-rehabilitation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Physiotherapeutic scoliosis-specific exercises (PSSE) have been proved to be effective in scoliosis rehabilitation. PSSE consist of a program of curve-specific exercise protocols which are individually adapted to a patients’ curve site, magnitude, and clinical characteristics. Specific PSSE are used to help relieve scoliosis symptoms. PSSE is not generalized physiotherapy exercises which are generic exercises usually consisting of low impact stretching and strengthening activities like yoga, Pilates and the Alexander technique but especially designed exercise for scoliosis patients that requires professional guidance. Wrong movement may cause severe damage to the spine again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the COVID-19 pandemic, Exercise at specific medical centres with crowd around is risky. Smart phone, however, is now prevalence all over the world. Almost every smart phone contains at least one 2D camera that can capture video stream. If we can use this device to track patients’ movement, it may be way more convenient for doctors to guide the patients remotely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Human pose estimation is one of the best matches of tracking patient movement at home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent years have witnessed learning-based human pose estimation getting popular in more scenarios with occlusions, where invisible areas for perception objects significantly affect accuracy. Existing methods mainly use convolutional neural networks as the backbone and get limited local features to recover the occluded part. Such an anti-occlusion pipeline often suffers from the challenges of self-occlusion scenery, where similar parts of occluders and occludees are ambiguous. In this case, we need to design a masked visual autoencoder for image processing and video streaming, which recovers occluded regions by extracting deep spatial information at a higher semantic level. This autoencoder can get better details inferred from global self-attention and thus improves accuracy. The gist is to train the autoencoder to extract key-point information from the joint tokens that are manually masked in a self-supervised manner to simulate the occlusion in video streaming. To use dataset more efficiently and extract more information from a single image, we generate several different positive samples simulating more occluded cases by randomly mask more patches in joint tokens. We also propose an end-to-end pipeline for training and inference, which can effectively reduce the dependency of annotated occluded datasets and can be further applied to other visual tasks. This pipeline can obtain a great computation saving with much fewer annotated datasets and hold a higher runtime performance over the SOTA ViT methods.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>