<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blockchain | PEILab</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/tags/blockchain/</link><atom:link href="https://peilab.netlify.app/tags/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Blockchain</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © The Pervasive Edge Intelligence Laboratory Reserved. 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://peilab.netlify.app/media/logo_hude7c550c9b1c4d0119cb1e6619a815ae_62586_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>Blockchain</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/tags/blockchain/</link></image><item><title>Next generation blockchain system</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/next-generation-blockchain-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/next-generation-blockchain-system/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our team aims at the next-generation blockchain system with scalability, security, privacy, and intelligence and our proposed architecture is composed of 6 layers as above. In the following, the details of these 6 layers will be explained from top to bottom.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Edge Application Layer in Blockchain-empowered Edge Learning</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/edge-application-layer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/edge-application-layer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Blockchain-empowered edge learning is a novel distributed learning architecture to dispense with a dedicated server in traditional distributed learning and provide trustworthy training for edge devices. It is based on a blockchain platform in which the edge devices for distributed learning participate in the consensus and commit and receive transactions about the learning process including edge data collection, edge model weights, training results, etc. However, existing blockchains cannot be directly used for swarm learning because their consensus protocols often commit transactions in blocks, each of which requires minutes, while swarm learning produces massive data about the learning processes in real-time. Moreover, the edge devices are often unable to meet the hardware requirement of the existing blockchain consensus such as the computation-intensive mining in Proof-of-Work (PoW). Therefore, we are going to design a streaming blockchain system and smart contract engine for swarm learning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Semantic Query and Index Layer in Semantic Blockchain Database</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/semantic-blockchain-database/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/semantic-blockchain-database/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Blockchain database is a new direction that constructs index on top of blockchain to provide rich query functionalities. The existing works are either insecure because the query process separates from the blockchain consensus, or inscalable because all the data needs to be stored in the block. Therefore, we propose an authenticated semantic database layer for blockchains. We design a hybrid on/off chain blockchain storage architecture in which the majority of blockchain storage is offloaded to the off-chain storage and a novel index structure named Merkle Semantic Trie (MST) is designed to be a secure and semantic bridge between on- and off-chain. Based on MST, MSTDB provides a variety of semantic query functions including multi-keyword query, range query, Top-K query, and cross-chain query. Besides, to improve the performance further, we design some index compression and query preprocessing techniques for our semantic database layer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>An Efficient Query Scheme for Hybrid Storage Blockchains based on Merkle Semantic Trie, Best Paper Award Runner Up received in SRDS 2020 (CCF-B).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intelligent Consensus Layer in Learning-Driven Dynamic Architecture</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/intelligent-consensus-layer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/intelligent-consensus-layer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Most existing blockchain systems adopt a static policy that cannot efciently deal with the dynamic environment in the blockchain system, i.e., joining and leaving of nodes, and malicious attack. Therefore, we propose a novel dynamic sharding-based blockchain framework to achieve a good balance between performance and security without compromising scalability under a dynamic environment. For the framework, a deep reinforcement learning (DRL)-based consensus is designed to acquire optimal sharding policies in a series of dynamic and high-dimensional environment states.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SkyChain: A Deep Reinforcement Learning-Empowered Dynamic Blockchain Sharding System, Best Paper Award Runner Up received in ICPP 2020 (CCF-B).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Layered Sharding Architecture for Blockchain</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/scalable-consensus-layer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/scalable-consensus-layer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a promising solution to blockchain scalability, sharding divides blockchain nodes into small groups called shards, splitting the workload. Existing works for sharding, however, are limited by cross-shard transactions, since they need to split each cross-shard transaction into multiple sub-transactions, each of which costs a consensus round to commit. To deal with the serious performance degradation brought by cross-shard transactions. Therefore, we propose a novel layered sharding architecture for blockchain and a cooperation-based layered sharding consensus. The basic idea is to allow shards to overlap, rather than isolating them completely, so that some nodes can locate in more than one shard. For cross-shard transactions, nodes located in the overlap of these shards can cooperative to verify, process and commit them directly and efficiently.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Pyramid: A Layered Sharding Blockchain System, INFOCOM 2021 (CCF-A).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sustainable Off-chain Payment Channel Network</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/fast-payment-layer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/fast-payment-layer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Payment channel network (PCN) is the most promising off-chain technologies to support massive micro payments for blockchain. The technology has been deployed in a number of blockchains including Bitcoin and Ethereum. For example, Lightning Network, a PCN built on top of Bitcoin, is currently able to provide a network capacity of about 200 million dollars, which is doubling every year. However, the existing PCN faces the challenge of sustainability, i.e., due to the imbalanced transfer in channels, the balance in one direction of channels gradually becomes exhausted, which makes the success ratio of payments in PCN suffers a major setback. Therefore, for the fast payment layer in our system, we propose a sustainable PCN based on a new idea of asynchronous agreement and design a new rebalancing protocol which can constantly balance the network without channel freezing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>CYCLE: Sustainable Off-Chain Payment Channel Network with Asynchronous Rebalancing, DSN 2022 (CCF-B).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hybrid On-/Off-Chain Distributed Storage</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/mass-storage-layer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/mass-storage-layer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Personal data produced from widely emerged cyberspace activities are expected to promote information dissemination and engagement, or even make business intelligence more powerful. However, the recent increase in social media incidents of illegal surveillance and data breaches raises questions about the current data ownership model, in which centralized applications collect and control large amounts of user data. We present SocialChain, which is a decentralized online data storage and sharing system based on blockchain that decouples user data and applications to return data ownership to the user. We adopt Personal Data Store to extend off-chain storage for the online data, set up an identity establishment mechanism that can support WebID-based authentication functions using a unique identity assignment (i.e., WebID) as well as certificateless cryptography, and design a general framework that leverages smart contracts to help securely store and share social data in an automated manner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SocialChain: Decoupling Social Data and Applications to Return Your Data Ownership, IEEE Transactions on Services Computing (CCF-B, JCR Q1), 2021.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Architectures and Methodologies for High Performance Sharding Blockchain</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/new-architectures-and-methodologies-for-high-performance-sharding-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/project/new-architectures-and-methodologies-for-high-performance-sharding-blockchain/</guid><description>&lt;p>Blockchain draws tremendous attention from academia and industry, since it can provide distributed ledgers with data transparency, integrity, and immutability to untrusted parties for various decentralized applications. However, it is still challenging for blockchain to deal with large-scale networks because of the limited scalability of the blockchain systems. Sharding is a novel blockchain architecture that is proved to significantly improve the scalability of blockchain. Its main idea is to divide blockchain nodes into small groups called shards, which can handle transactions in parallel. To exploit the shortages of blockchain sharding for real application environment, we conduct two research projects as follows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, to deal with the serious performance degradation brought by cross-shard transactions, we propose a novel layered sharding architecture for blockchain and a cooperation-based layered sharding consensus. The basic idea is to allow shards to overlap, rather than isolating them completely, so that some nodes can locate in more than one shard. For cross-shard transactions, nodes located in the overlap of these shards can cooperative to verify, process and commit them directly and efficiently.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure id="figure-blockchain-and-training">
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >
&lt;img alt="Blockchain and Training"
src="https://peilab.netlify.app/project/new-architectures-and-methodologies-for-high-performance-sharding-blockchain/picture1.svg"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>
Blockchain and Training
&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Second, most existing blockchain sharding systems adopt a static sharding policy that cannot efciently deal with the dynamic environment in the blockchain system, i.e., joining and leaving of nodes, and malicious attack. We propose a novel dynamic sharding-based blockchain framework to achieve a good balance between performance and security without compromising scalability under a dynamic environment. For the framework, a deep reinforcement learning (DRL)-based consensus is designed to acquire optimal sharding policies in a series of dynamic and high-dimensional environment states.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>