<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News | PEILab</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/post/</link><atom:link href="https://peilab.netlify.app/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>News</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © The Pervasive Edge Intelligence Laboratory Reserved. 2023</copyright><image><url>https://peilab.netlify.app/media/logo_hude7c550c9b1c4d0119cb1e6619a815ae_62586_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>News</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/post/</link></image><item><title>Zero Dynamic Medical Technology won Gold Medal at Geneva Inventions Expo</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/zero-dynamic-medical-technology-won-gold-medal-at-geneva-inventions-expo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/zero-dynamic-medical-technology-won-gold-medal-at-geneva-inventions-expo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congratulations to Zhenda Xu and Professor Song Guo for being awarded Gold Medal at the 48th International Exhibition of Inventions Geneva (Geneva Inventions Expo), widely regarded as among the most important annual global events devoted exclusively to inventions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="1.jpg" alt="1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="2.jpg" alt="2">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.polyu.edu.hk/media/media-releases/2023/0429_polyu-wins-record-breaking-number-of-awards-at-geneva-inventions-expo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Related Links&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prof. Song Guo as one of the world’s most highly cited researchers this year</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/prof.-song-guo-as-one-of-the-worlds-most-highly-cited-researchers-this-year/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/prof.-song-guo-as-one-of-the-worlds-most-highly-cited-researchers-this-year/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congratulations to Professor Song Guo for being recognised in the list of “Highly Cited Researchers 2022”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Hong Kong Polytechnic University (PolyU) has the third highest number in Hong Kong of the world’s most highly cited researchers this year, with 12 PolyU academics (including two former PolyU members) being recognised in the list of “Highly Cited Researchers 2022” by Clarivate Analytics for their significant research impact, reflected in their publication of multiple papers that have been frequently cited by fellow academics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A total of 6,938 researchers from 69 countries and regions with a diverse range of research fields are named as Highly Cited Researchers in 2022. The list identifies the most influential scholars around the world, determined by the production of multiple highly cited papers that rank in the top 1% by citations for field and year in the Web of Science citation index over the last decade.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The inclusion of 12 PolyU academics in the list is a testament to the University’s pursuit of research excellence and commitment to positive societal impact on various fronts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.polyu.edu.hk/media/media-releases/2022/1117_twelve-polyu-academics-recognised-amongst-the-worlds-most-highly-cited-researchers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Related Links&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Congratulations to Jie Zhang for her PhD graduation!</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/congratulations-to-jie-zhang-for-her-phd-graduation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/congratulations-to-jie-zhang-for-her-phd-graduation/</guid><description>&lt;p>We would like to express our heartfelt congratulations to Dr. Jie Zhang for the acquisition of her PhD degree.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jie’s research was focusing on edge computing, federated learning, and computer vision. She published more than 15 papers during her PhD including NIPS, CVPR, DAC, TC, TPDS etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She is now working as a Post-doctoral Fellow in PEILab, PolyU, Hong Kong. Wishing all the best for her future career!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="j1.jpg" alt="j1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="j2.jpg" alt="j2">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Congratulations to Jingcai Guo for his PhD graduation!</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/congratulations-to-jingcai-guo-for-his-phd-graduation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/congratulations-to-jingcai-guo-for-his-phd-graduation/</guid><description>&lt;p>We would like to express our heartfelt congratulations to Dr. Jingcai Guo for the acquisition of his Ph.D. degree. Although Jingcai received his Ph.D. degree in 2021, his graduation ceremony has been postponed to this year due to the impacts of COVID-19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jingcai’s research was focusing on machine learning and edge AI, with a particular focus on zero/few-shot learning, federated learning, representation learning, and model compression.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From 2021 to 2022, he was an Associate Professor with School of Computing and Artificial Intelligence, Southwestern University of Finance and Economics, China. Start from September 2022, he came back to Hong Kong and joined Department of Computing, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, as a Research Assistant Professor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Congratulations again to Dr. Jingcai Guo!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="c1.jpg" alt="c1">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Our newly admitted PhD student Ruibin Li is one of the new HKPFS 2022-2023 awardees</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/our-newly-admitted-phd-student-ruibin-li-is-one-of-the-new-hkpfs-2022-2023-awardees/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/our-newly-admitted-phd-student-ruibin-li-is-one-of-the-new-hkpfs-2022-2023-awardees/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congratulations! Our newly admitted PhD student, Ruibin Li, is one of the new HKPFS 2022-2023 awardees. Established by the Research Grants Council (RGC) of Hong Kong in 2009, the Hong Kong PhD Fellowship Scheme (HKPFS) aims at attracting the brilliant minds to pursue their PhD studies in Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s universities. Only a few students, who could demonstrate outstanding qualities of academic performance, research ability / potential, communication and interpersonal skills, and leadership abilities, are awarded every year. His future research will focus on edge computing, reinforcement learning, federated learning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prof. Song Guo as a New Member Elected into the Academia Europaea</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/prof.-song-guo-as-a-new-member-elected-into-the-academia-europaea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/prof.-song-guo-as-a-new-member-elected-into-the-academia-europaea/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congratulations to Professor Song Guo for being elected into the Academia Europaea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The object of Academia Europaea is the advancement and propagation of excellence in scholarship in the humanities, law, the economic, social, and political sciences, mathematics, medicine, and all branches of natural and technological sciences anywhere in the world for the public benefit and for the advancement of the education of the public of all ages. The aim of the Academy is to promote European research, advise governments and international organisations in scientific matters, and further interdisciplinary and international research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.ae-info.org/ae/Acad_Main/List_of_Members/Elected%20members%202022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Related Links&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Grand Project-The development and application of open system of edge computing for human-machine collaboration</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/grand-project-the-development-and-application-of-open-system-of-edge-computing-for-human-machine-collaboration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/grand-project-the-development-and-application-of-open-system-of-edge-computing-for-human-machine-collaboration/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Key-Area Research and Development Program of Guangdong Province on the New Generation of Artificial Intelligence, Grand Project &amp;ldquo;The development and application of open system of edge computing for human-machine collaboration&amp;rdquo;, 2021-2024, Co-PI, 34,000,000 RMB.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project-6G-Wireless Access and Connectivity for an Intelligent and Sustainable World</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/project-6g-wireless-access-and-connectivity-for-an-intelligent-and-sustainable-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/project-6g-wireless-access-and-connectivity-for-an-intelligent-and-sustainable-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>RGC Areas of Excellence Scheme (AoE), &amp;ldquo;6G: Wireless Access and Connectivity for an Intelligent and Sustainable World&amp;rdquo;, 2023-2027, Co-PC, 87,304,000 HKD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project-Editable Learning with Fast Adaptation over Evolutionary Edges</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/project-editable-learning-with-fast-adaptation-over-evolutionary-edges/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/project-editable-learning-with-fast-adaptation-over-evolutionary-edges/</guid><description>&lt;p>RGC General Research Fund (GRF), &amp;ldquo;Editable Learning with Fast Adaptation over Evolutionary Edges&amp;rdquo;, 2023-2025, PI, 1,145,729 HKD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TinyML Systems for Edge Intelligence</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/tinyml-systems-for-edge-intelligence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/tinyml-systems-for-edge-intelligence/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/xyuem7pqtu9L3kyI5F06eg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Related Links&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This talk will focus on the field of &lt;strong>Edge Learning&lt;/strong>. Specifically, learning paradigms, fundamental theories, and enabling technologies for Edge Learning consist the main components of this tutorial. We will first explain the background and motivation for ML running at the network edge. Then, we will review the challenge issues existing in Edge Learning. Furthermore, we will provide an overview of the overarching architectures, frameworks, and emerging key technologies for learning performance, security, privacy, and incentive issues toward training/inference at the network edge. Finally, we will discuss future research opportunities on Edge Learning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Deep Reinforcement Learning Based Offloading Game in Edge Computing, 2020 Best Paper Award for IEEE Transactions on Computers</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/a-deep-reinforcement-learning-based-offloading-game-in-edge-computing-2020-best-paper-award-for-ieee-transactions-on-computers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/a-deep-reinforcement-learning-based-offloading-game-in-edge-computing-2020-best-paper-award-for-ieee-transactions-on-computers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congratulations to Professor Song Guo for 2020 Best Paper Award for IEEE Transactions on Computers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="award-certificate">Award Certificate&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure id="figure-certificate-of-internet-contest">
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >
&lt;img alt="Certificate of Internet&amp;#43; Contest" srcset="
/news/a-deep-reinforcement-learning-based-offloading-game-in-edge-computing-2020-best-paper-award-for-ieee-transactions-on-computers/1_hu81e7f41de781ee2d925ac430c3bfe5bf_87227_b617de783ce47f47be04f7e9c1534146.png 400w,
/news/a-deep-reinforcement-learning-based-offloading-game-in-edge-computing-2020-best-paper-award-for-ieee-transactions-on-computers/1_hu81e7f41de781ee2d925ac430c3bfe5bf_87227_5e3ef56740906d2a32d7a2368d1f221a.png 760w,
/news/a-deep-reinforcement-learning-based-offloading-game-in-edge-computing-2020-best-paper-award-for-ieee-transactions-on-computers/1_hu81e7f41de781ee2d925ac430c3bfe5bf_87227_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_2.png 1200w"
src="https://peilab.netlify.app/news/a-deep-reinforcement-learning-based-offloading-game-in-edge-computing-2020-best-paper-award-for-ieee-transactions-on-computers/1_hu81e7f41de781ee2d925ac430c3bfe5bf_87227_b617de783ce47f47be04f7e9c1534146.png"
width="760"
height="584"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>
Certificate of Internet+ Contest
&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>New book: Edge Learning for Distributed Big Data Analytics</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/new-book-edge-learning-for-distributed-big-data-analytics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/new-book-edge-learning-for-distributed-big-data-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/books/edge-learning-for-distributed-big-data-analytics/37D8FC64C94641362BE9AFCDBCD0AD9B" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Related Links&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>零动医疗科技荣获“2021年度香港资讯及通讯科技奖-学生创新大奖”</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/%E9%9B%B6%E5%8A%A8%E5%8C%BB%E7%96%97%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E8%8D%A3%E8%8E%B72021%E5%B9%B4%E5%BA%A6%E9%A6%99%E6%B8%AF%E8%B5%84%E8%AE%AF%E5%8F%8A%E9%80%9A%E8%AE%AF%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E5%A5%96-%E5%AD%A6%E7%94%9F%E5%88%9B%E6%96%B0%E5%A4%A7%E5%A5%96/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/%E9%9B%B6%E5%8A%A8%E5%8C%BB%E7%96%97%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E8%8D%A3%E8%8E%B72021%E5%B9%B4%E5%BA%A6%E9%A6%99%E6%B8%AF%E8%B5%84%E8%AE%AF%E5%8F%8A%E9%80%9A%E8%AE%AF%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E5%A5%96-%E5%AD%A6%E7%94%9F%E5%88%9B%E6%96%B0%E5%A4%A7%E5%A5%96/</guid><description>&lt;p>深圳零动医疗科技有限公司在众多优秀竞争企业中脱颖而出，同时斩获2021香港资讯及通讯科技奖-学生创新大奖及学生创新“大专或以上”金奖。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/NElnRdORmRUFyCqN-oqUFQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Related Links&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="award-certificate">Award Certificate&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure id="figure-certificate-of-internet-contest">
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >
&lt;img alt="Certificate of Internet&amp;#43; Contest" srcset="
/news/%E9%9B%B6%E5%8A%A8%E5%8C%BB%E7%96%97%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E8%8D%A3%E8%8E%B72021%E5%B9%B4%E5%BA%A6%E9%A6%99%E6%B8%AF%E8%B5%84%E8%AE%AF%E5%8F%8A%E9%80%9A%E8%AE%AF%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E5%A5%96-%E5%AD%A6%E7%94%9F%E5%88%9B%E6%96%B0%E5%A4%A7%E5%A5%96/1_hue2d27a142eaeea6e453c138074340131_218693_0fc73eea1509f380e9764adcf5094464.jpg 400w,
/news/%E9%9B%B6%E5%8A%A8%E5%8C%BB%E7%96%97%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E8%8D%A3%E8%8E%B72021%E5%B9%B4%E5%BA%A6%E9%A6%99%E6%B8%AF%E8%B5%84%E8%AE%AF%E5%8F%8A%E9%80%9A%E8%AE%AF%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E5%A5%96-%E5%AD%A6%E7%94%9F%E5%88%9B%E6%96%B0%E5%A4%A7%E5%A5%96/1_hue2d27a142eaeea6e453c138074340131_218693_a5d12a2cb766d848b624a5e00e6686bb.jpg 760w,
/news/%E9%9B%B6%E5%8A%A8%E5%8C%BB%E7%96%97%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E8%8D%A3%E8%8E%B72021%E5%B9%B4%E5%BA%A6%E9%A6%99%E6%B8%AF%E8%B5%84%E8%AE%AF%E5%8F%8A%E9%80%9A%E8%AE%AF%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E5%A5%96-%E5%AD%A6%E7%94%9F%E5%88%9B%E6%96%B0%E5%A4%A7%E5%A5%96/1_hue2d27a142eaeea6e453c138074340131_218693_1200x1200_fit_q100_lanczos.jpg 1200w"
src="https://peilab.netlify.app/news/%E9%9B%B6%E5%8A%A8%E5%8C%BB%E7%96%97%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E8%8D%A3%E8%8E%B72021%E5%B9%B4%E5%BA%A6%E9%A6%99%E6%B8%AF%E8%B5%84%E8%AE%AF%E5%8F%8A%E9%80%9A%E8%AE%AF%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E5%A5%96-%E5%AD%A6%E7%94%9F%E5%88%9B%E6%96%B0%E5%A4%A7%E5%A5%96/1_hue2d27a142eaeea6e453c138074340131_218693_0fc73eea1509f380e9764adcf5094464.jpg"
width="541"
height="760"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>
Certificate of Internet+ Contest
&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Prof. Song Guo as a New Fellow Elected into the Canadian Academy of Engineering</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/prof.-song-guo-as-a-new-fellow-elected-into-the-canadian-academy-of-engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/prof.-song-guo-as-a-new-fellow-elected-into-the-canadian-academy-of-engineering/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congratulations to Professor Song Guo for being elected into the Canadian Academy of Engineering.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Canadian Academy of Engineering (CAE) is the national institution through which individuals, who have made outstanding contributions to engineering in Canada, provide strategic advice on matters of critical importance to Canada and to Canadians. The CAE is an independent, self-governing, and non-profit organization established in 1987. Fellows of the CAE are nominated and elected by their peers, in view of their distinguished achievements and career-long service. Fellows of the Canadian Academy of Engineering are committed to ensuring that Canada’s engineering expertise is applied to the benefit of all Canadians.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Canadian Academy of Engineering works in close cooperation with other senior academies in Canada and internationally. It is a founding member of the Council of Canadian Academies, along with the Royal Society of Canada (RSC) and the Canadian Academy of Health Sciences (CAHS). The CAE is also a member of the International Council of Academies of Engineering and Technological Sciences (CAETS), which includes 31 similar national bodies around the world and the Partnership Group for Science and Engineering (PAGSE), an association of more than 20 Canadian organizations in science and engineering, whose mandate is to educate and inform federal Parliamentarians, decision makers and other leaders of the importance and significance of Canadian research and innovation to economic development, and society as a whole.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cae-acg.ca/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/CAE-2021-News-release.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Related Links&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dr. Body won Sliver Awards on the "Internet+" and "Challenge Cup" Contest</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/dr.-body-won-sliver-awards-on-the-internet-and-challenge-cup-contest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/dr.-body-won-sliver-awards-on-the-internet-and-challenge-cup-contest/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congratulations to Zhenda Xu and Professor Song Guo for being awarded Sliver on &amp;ldquo;Internet+&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Challenge Cup&amp;rdquo; Contest.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="about-the-internet-contest">About the &amp;ldquo;Internet+&amp;rdquo; Contest&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &amp;ldquo;Internet+&amp;rdquo; Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition has been successfully held five times since 2015, and has become the world&amp;rsquo;s largest innovation and entrepreneurship competition for college students. In 2020, the competition drew 6.32 million participants (1.48 million teams) from 4,146 colleges and universities in 124 countries and regions. Over 1,000 professionals were invited to judge the competition and mentor the participants, among whom were investors, entrepreneurs, startup incubator mentors, and innovation and entrepreneurship education experts from China and abroad. Many high-quality projects stood out, gaining market visibility and investment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More than half of the top 100 universities in the world participated in this competition. The quality of the competition hit a record high, and the proportion of silver medals and above awards in the competition was about 0.03%.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="about-the-challenge-cup-contest">About the &amp;ldquo;Challenge Cup&amp;rdquo; Contest&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &amp;ldquo;Challenge Cup&amp;rdquo; contest, initiated in 1989, has attracted submissions by about one million students from colleges and universities in Mainland China, Hong Kong, Macao, and Taiwan. As a national guide and authoritative competition, the Challenge Cup is known as the &amp;ldquo;Olympics&amp;rdquo; of science and technology for Chinese college students. It is also a window to show Chinese college students' creativity in science and technology and an arena to select students of high quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="award-certificate">Award Certificate&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure id="figure-certificate-of-internet-contest">
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >
&lt;img alt="Certificate of Internet&amp;#43; Contest" srcset="
/news/dr.-body-won-sliver-awards-on-the-internet-and-challenge-cup-contest/image1_hu11f37fe27a3e32902d6596f910d458f9_3594960_2937b7036960af1a0343d8c6e76d69c6.jpg 400w,
/news/dr.-body-won-sliver-awards-on-the-internet-and-challenge-cup-contest/image1_hu11f37fe27a3e32902d6596f910d458f9_3594960_fef0dbfc54a650904b6481773bd8e781.jpg 760w,
/news/dr.-body-won-sliver-awards-on-the-internet-and-challenge-cup-contest/image1_hu11f37fe27a3e32902d6596f910d458f9_3594960_1200x1200_fit_q100_lanczos.jpg 1200w"
src="https://peilab.netlify.app/news/dr.-body-won-sliver-awards-on-the-internet-and-challenge-cup-contest/image1_hu11f37fe27a3e32902d6596f910d458f9_3594960_2937b7036960af1a0343d8c6e76d69c6.jpg"
width="760"
height="570"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>
Certificate of Internet+ Contest
&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure id="figure-certificate-of-challenge-cup-contest">
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >
&lt;img alt="Certificate of Challenge Cup Contest" srcset="
/news/dr.-body-won-sliver-awards-on-the-internet-and-challenge-cup-contest/image2_huc2ea0f0ae28c0878cdc236a5ef66ea99_3187881_0d6d9d74e9ceaf2107b0de1956f4ca8a.jpg 400w,
/news/dr.-body-won-sliver-awards-on-the-internet-and-challenge-cup-contest/image2_huc2ea0f0ae28c0878cdc236a5ef66ea99_3187881_60e215656efd771f22693a9c52364db5.jpg 760w,
/news/dr.-body-won-sliver-awards-on-the-internet-and-challenge-cup-contest/image2_huc2ea0f0ae28c0878cdc236a5ef66ea99_3187881_1200x1200_fit_q100_lanczos.jpg 1200w"
src="https://peilab.netlify.app/news/dr.-body-won-sliver-awards-on-the-internet-and-challenge-cup-contest/image2_huc2ea0f0ae28c0878cdc236a5ef66ea99_3187881_0d6d9d74e9ceaf2107b0de1956f4ca8a.jpg"
width="760"
height="570"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>
Certificate of Challenge Cup Contest
&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Professor Song Guo was elected as the 2020 CCF Distinguished Speaker</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/professor-song-guo-was-elected-as-the-2020-ccf-distinguished-speaker/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/professor-song-guo-was-elected-as-the-2020-ccf-distinguished-speaker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congratulations to Professor Song Guo for being elected as the 2020 CCF Distinguished Speaker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.ccf.org.cn/Membership/Individual_member/Updates/2021-01-19/721988.shtml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Related Links&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SkyChain: A Deep Reinforcement Learning-Empowered Dynamic Blockchain Sharding System, Best Paper Award Runner Up received in ICPP 2020</title><link>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/skychain-a-deep-reinforcement-learning-empowered-dynamic-blockchain-sharding-system-best-paper-award-runner-up-received-in-icpp-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilab.netlify.app/news/skychain-a-deep-reinforcement-learning-empowered-dynamic-blockchain-sharding-system-best-paper-award-runner-up-received-in-icpp-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congratulations to Professor Song Guo for Best Paper Award Runner Up received in ICPP 2020.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://jnamaral.github.io/icpp20/program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Related Links&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>